<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>semicomplete</title>
    <link>https://semicomplete.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on semicomplete</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 08:58:56 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://semicomplete.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Office Automation</title>
      <link>https://semicomplete.com/blog/home-office-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 08:58:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://semicomplete.com/blog/home-office-automation/</guid>
      <description>I built a little digital Rube-Goldberg device for my office. When I turn my desk power switch on, a little microcontroller brings my workstation and stereo online.
My desk has a keyboard and monitor, but no computer. The computer lives in the closet a few feet away. Also in this closet is my stereo which drives audio to for the office. This makes my desk cleaner and quieter, but makes it hard to hit the power buttons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> xdotool  -  fake keyboard/mouse input, window management, and more 
</title>
      <link>https://semicomplete.com/projects/xdotool/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 21:46:35 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://semicomplete.com/projects/xdotool/</guid>
      <description>What is xdotool? This tool lets you simulate keyboard input and mouse activity, move and resize windows, etc. It does this using X11&amp;rsquo;s XTEST extension and other Xlib functions.
Additionally, you can search for windows and move, resize, hide, and modify window properties like the title. If your window manager supports it, you can use xdotool to switch desktops, move windows between desktops, and change the number of desktops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puppet &#34;pure fact-driven&#34; nodeless configuration
</title>
      <link>https://semicomplete.com/blog/geekery/puppet-nodeless-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2010 01:14:37 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://semicomplete.com/blog/geekery/puppet-nodeless-configuration/</guid>
      <description>Truth should guide your configuration management tools.
Truth in this case is: what machines you have, properties of those machines, roles for those machines, etc. For example &amp;ldquo;foo-1.a.example.com is a webserver&amp;rdquo; is a piece of truth. Where and how you store truth is up to you and out of scope for this post.
My goal is to have truth steer everything about my infrastructure. Roles, jobs, and even long-term one-offs get put into the truth source (like a machine role, etc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> fex  -  flexible token-field extraction 
</title>
      <link>https://semicomplete.com/projects/fex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2010 00:13:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://semicomplete.com/projects/fex/</guid>
      <description>What is fex? Fex is a powerful field extraction tool. Fex provides a very concise language for tokenizeing strings and extracting fields.
The basic usage model is that you provide a series of delimiter and field selection pairs. Tokens can be any character, while field selections have a specific syntax.
Download Releases are available on GitHub.
Sometimes simpler than cut and awk cut(1) from GNU coreutils (on Linux) does not support negative offsets, so you cannot ask cut to only show you the Nth field from the end.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>